It's an ayu.
Look, there is an eel!
A small and cute sand eel!
Ms. Kurumi Takase of the idol group Beyooooonds
the only place in Japan where one can study fisheries in Tochigi, Yamanashi Prefecture.
Tochigi Prefectural Pato High School, the only school in Japan where students can study fisheries in Tochigi, Yamanashi Prefecture.
Thank you for watching!
Lots of fish at Pato High School
To Pato High School
This time we would like to introduce
Tochigi Prefectural Pato High School
The Nakagawa River flows nearby.
Fisheries have long flourished along the Nakagawa River
It is an indispensable place to talk about the charm of Tochigi Prefecture.
This school has a department where students can learn about fisheries in such a Nakagawa basin.
This is the school where you can learn about fisheries in the Nakagawa basin.
This school became a topic of conversation last year.
It is also famous as the model high school of the novel "Nakasugi". I would like to go there to see what kind of school it really is.
Let's go there!
Tochigi Prefectural Matou High School in Nakagawa-cho.
The fisheries department at this high school was established by Takayuki Nakagawa as a department specializing in fisheries for the promotion of fisheries in Tochigi Prefecture.
The Department of Fisheries was founded in 1972 to establish a department specializing in fisheries in Nakagawa Takayuki.
It was established in 1972.
As the only department specializing in inland fisheries in the country
We have been consolidating our achievements for more than 50 years
Highly symptomatic
There are a lot of them
Good afternoon.
What does the Fisheries Department at Horseheads High School offer?
The Fisheries Department at Matou High School is a general fisheries department specializing in freshwater.
You can learn about food production, aquaculture, and the waterside environment.
By the way, what kind of things do you do and what kind of things do your students do?
What kind of research do your students do?
We have a class called "research project," which is similar to a university student's thesis, for two hours a week from the second grade, and two hours each for the second and third grades.
For example, eels.
Some of the students are engaged in eel farming.
Some students are learning about the river environment.
Some students are studying the environment of the river, and others are studying the freshwater shishimi, which is a bit of a maniac.
Miyakoda Nago spawns, for example.
Some students are studying the bivalve mollusks that Miyakoda Nago spawns
There are students who are doing maniacal research in a variety of fields.
Every year, there are students who are doing maniacal research in a variety of fields.
Today, the third-year students of the Fisheries Department are working at a training site a little bit away from the school.
I would like to take you there.
So I'd like to take you there.
The Fisheries Department's training site is about 10 minutes away by car.
Here, they breed ayu (sweetfish), eels, and basking sharks, and conduct a variety of practical training.
A variety of practical training is being conducted here.
What are the students doing in the back?
We are shipping ayu today.
Shipping ayu!
They're putting a lot of ayu into nets and putting them into boxes over and over again.
How many ayu are there?
Are they there?
We produced about 500 kilograms this year.
500 kilos!
How many fish?
I think there were about 10,000 or so.
If you want, you can work with the set to pick up the ayu.
Is that all right?
Yes, sir.
I've never done it before. It's my first time.
Give it a try.
I'll give it a try.
I'm up for it.
Docho, the first of the next generation.
I feel like I'm being cut off a little bit.
I'll do my best.
Mr. Takase immediately entered the pond.
There are a lot of sweetfish.
There's a lot of ayu here.
They're here, but....
They're fast!
They run away so fast!
One fish got in!
One got in!
With the help of the students, we decided to try again.
We're going to drive them in for now.
If you could scoop up the ashes from the bottom where they're bouncing around like a ball...
I could tell from the bottom.
If you do it, we'll get a lot of ash in there.
I'd appreciate it if you could do it.
Great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great!
Great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great.
Now, please.
Yes, please.
Wow, that's great.
You're so heavy.
It's so heavy.
Here you go.
Here we go.
That's great.
I got a lot in!
This is so much fun.
I got it!
Check the size of the fish and freeze them in bags
We put them in bags and freeze them one by one.
What's unique about ayu here?
Ayu has a very distinctive smell.
What kind of smell? What is its distinctive smell?
It's like a urica plant.
Like a cucumber.
That may be true.
Mr. Takase, ayu is also called a cucumber fish because it smells like a cucumber.
It's also called "Takumi fish" because it smells like cucumber.
What's this one over here?
The ayu over here...
For example, this ayu is a beautiful ayu.
If you look at this ayu
This ayu is a beautiful ayu.
We separate the ayu that is not in good shape from the one that is bumpy.
We use them in other ways, for example, as fishing grounds.
Where do you go to school now?
I come from a neighboring town called Mascara Mountain City.
My neighbor, Kobayashi, is from Fukushima. From Fukushima.
I've always loved the search business.
That's why I'm going to this school.
I see.
So the fisheries department was a deciding factor in your decision to attend this high school.
was the deciding factor in your decision to go to this high school.
Yes, that's how I put it.
What do you do here?
I'm working on freezing.
Freezing.
Why did you choose to go into aquaculture?
Can I ask you why you chose this aquaculture?
Yes, sir.
I'm from an ocean prefecture.
I used to go fishing with my brother.
After I moved here.
I heard that they deal with freshwater fish.
I enrolled in the Fisheries Department at Battle High School.
I see.
I've had the chance to go to Yanagihara since I was little.
I had the chance to eat ayu (sweetfish).
That's why I wanted to enroll here.
In the Fisheries Department, in addition to practical training in handling fish like this
As part of the education to become familiar with the water
and canoeing in a nearby river as part of the education to familiarize oneself with water.
In the afternoon, the students change into white coats.
In the afternoon, students change into white coats
good night.
We were doing something else.
What is this work now?
They are sealing and rolling up canned sweetfish in oil, a practical training product.
Is this ayu caught here, of course?
Yes, it's from last year, but it's ayu that the students raised during their training.
I see. And this canned food?
Yes.
Are these canned products sold somewhere?
We usually sell them at events.
This year, at the end of October, there is an industrial education fair in Tochigi.
We will be selling at the booth of this fisheries family.
At this Wato High School's Fisheries Department, we have this kind of hands-on training.
Do you have a lot of classes like this?
Do you have a lot of practical classes here at Wato High School?
Yes, as the school year progresses, the number of practical classes increases.
In food production, we have a class called "food production" from the second grade, and this is a part of that class.
Now, after leaving the training site, Mr. Takase returned to school.
It's now time for after-school activities.
It seems that Matou High School has its own club activities, so I'd like to go and check it out.
Excuse me.
There's a lot of aquariums here.
What kind of activities does this club do?
We're the Fisheries Science Club.
As you can see, there are a lot of tanks here.
As you can see, we have a lot of tanks, and our students collect fish from the nearby river.
Some students collect fish from the nearby river, some keep them as a hobby, and some keep them in their own tanks.
And each student has his or her own way of doing research.
We have a club where students can learn various methods of keeping fish.
We are a club that conducts such activities.
I've been wondering about this since I came into this classroom.
This big fish.
What is this fish called?
This fish is called Raijo.
Raijo?
Plus, my friend from Gunma.
He caught this fish from a local canal.
From the canal?
One of the most unique features of this fish is that it breathes air.
They are air breathers.
Here's a picture of a lynus putting its mouth above the surface of the water and breathing air.
You can observe the ecology of the fish here.
Here is a row of tanks.
There are a lot of cute little fish.
What kind of fish is this?
This fish is called an iyakotanago (bitterling).
Iyakotanago
It is a very rare fish that lives only in a limited number of waterways in Tochigi Prefecture.
Because of its rarity, it is designated as an endangered species and a natural monument, so it is prohibited to keep or catch without a permit.
We keep them here with special permission.
The Fisheries Science Research Department also breeds a variety of other fish.
You can see a scene like an aquarium.
This is only possible at Matou High School, which has a fisheries science department.
This time, we visited the Fisheries Department of Matou High School.
I was able to assist in the ayu harvesting and processing process...
I also visited the Fisheries Science Research Club.
In addition, there is a club called the Fisheries Science Research Club, which provides an environment where each student can research what they are interested in.
I think I was able to learn about the charm of Tochigi Prefecture one more time.
This time, we will give away Ayu Monaka to five winners!
Please write down your thoughts on the program and apply for the giveaway!